In the first video about Hybrid A*,
在有关混合 A* 的第一个视频中
the update equations that we used were somewhat
我们使用了一个更新方程
generic to most X Y field configuration spaces.
这个方程对于绝大部分具有 X Y 域的配置空间是通用的
In particular, we don't specify what Omega is.
特别是 我们没有标明 Omega 代表什么
Omega is the heading rate of change.
Omega 是有关变化的首要比率
Now for some robots,
对一些机器人而言
it might be that we can specify any omega independently of its state.
我们可以将 Omega 指定为独立的与其状态无关的值
But that would mean that the robot can turn around its Z axis without constraints.
但是那将意味着 机器人可以无限制地绕着它的 Z 轴转动
For car though, this is not very realistic,
对于汽车 这并不现实
and we should probably use the bicycle model.
我们或许应该使用自行车模型
This gives us an equation for Omega like this.
这给了我们一个和 Omega 等价的东西
Here, 'L' is the distance between the front and rear axle,
这里 L 是前后轴之间的距离
'δ' is the steering angle and ⱴ is the constant positive velocity.
δ 是转向角 ? 是值为正的恒定速度
Now, for our Hybrid A* algorithm,
现在 对于我们的混合 A* 算法
we need to decide which configuration can be reached from the current node considered,
我们需要决定 从我们当前处理的节点可以到达哪个配置
in order to add them to the open set.
并把它加入开放集合
In practice, we would probably use some number of
实践中 我们可能会使用一些转向角的值
steering angles between maximum left steer and maximum right steer angle.
这些值位于最大左右转向角之间
But the more different Deltas you add the longer it takes for your algorithm to complete.
但是 我们添加的 Delta 越多 我们的算法计算的时间越长
Therefore, in this example,
因此 在这个例子中
we will only choose three angles to pick delta from;
我们的 delat 只会从3个角度值中选择
the maximum left steering angle,
最大左转向角
zero steering angle and the maximum right steering angle.
0转向角 以及最大右转向角
In the case of a car that can turn its wheels 35 degrees at most,
如果一辆车的转向角最大值为35度
that would be -35, 0 and 35.
这3个值将是 -35 0 35
This allows us to expand the search tree with three new motion primitives;
这使我们可以用3种新的基本运动来扩展搜索树
go straight, steer left and steer right.
直行 左转 右转
Let's see how that works in a robot maze.
我们来看一下 在一个机器人迷宫中 搜索是如何展开的
Let's say we have a maze like this.
假设我们的迷宫是这样的
The red square is the goal and this is the start position.
红色方块是目标 这里是开始点
The first thing we would do is add this cell to open list.
我们第一步要做的是把这个格子加入 open 列表
I'll use gray to indicate that.
我用灰色来标示它
And then we would generate three trajectories,
接下来 我们会生成3条轨迹
the one for going straight,
第一条是直行
the one for turning right,
第二条是右转
the one for turning left.
第三条是左转
And in this case, we can discard the trajectories that go off the map or collide.
这里 我们可以丢弃那些指向地图之外的轨迹 以及会产生碰撞的轨迹
This gives us one new cell to open, which we do,
这样我们只剩一个新的单元格子 我们继续处理它
and then we mark the first cell closed which am indicating with this check-mark.
然后 我们把第一个单元格标记为关闭状态 用这个符号标记一下
Now, there is only one open cell so I choose to expend that one next.
现在 图上只有一个打开的单元格 我们接着扩展它
And again, I generate the three trajectories from this stage,
我们再次为它生成3条轨迹
one of them is infeasible,
这一条轨迹行不通
so let's not keep looking at it.
我们可以忽略它
And this leaves us with two new cells to open.
这样我们只面对两个新的单元格
I close the previous.
现在我关闭刚才的单元格
Now there are two choices of what cell to expand.
现在我们面临选择 用哪一个单元格去做扩展
Assuming i have some heuristic that values being closer to the goal,
假定我已经有一些启发值 这些值告诉我哪个格子更靠近目标
I choose the cell on the right,
然后我选择右边的格子
and then generate trajectories from this new state.
接着我继续为这个新的单元格生成轨迹
Note, how, in all these steps,
大家注意一下 在上面过程中
I'm keeping track of,
我不仅仅跟踪
not just what cell I am in,
当前所在的单元格
but also where in that cell I am, including orientation.
而且还会跟踪自身的位置 以及朝向
In practice, we could also use a three state space that include heading.
实践中 我们同样会使用三维的状态空间 其中包括朝向
If we don't do that, then we're likely to prematurely close cells.
如果不这么做 我们很可能会过早关闭单元格
I'm not doing it that way here,
这个例子中我并没有使用三维状态空间
mostly because it's harder to visualize.
主要是因为它很难可视化显示出来
Let's keep going. I have three new cells to open.
我们继续 现在我面临着三个新的单元格
I have to close the previous cell,
我先得关闭之前的一个
find the best option in the set of open cells and repeat.
然后从新单元格中找出一个最佳选择 然后继续上述过程
Again leaving me with three new cells to add to the open list.
再一次 我又有了3个新单元格要添加到 open 列表
Which means I can close
这意味着我现在可以关闭先前的单元格
the the previous cells and things get a little more interesting here.
事情到这里变得有趣起来
My heuristic will probably suggest that I expand
启发函数可能会建议我扩展到右下方单元格
the lower right cell and generate trajectories from there.
再从哪里继续生成轨迹
But this time, all of them would collide with the wall.
但是 如果这样选择 我们就走入了死胡同
Therefore, I don't need to add any new cell to the open set.
因此 我不需要给开放列表添加新的单元格
Now, since I did expand this cell I have to mark it closed,
现在 因为我从这个单元格做的扩展 我不得不关闭它
and then I can look at my remaining open cells.
然后 我可以查看我剩余的打开的单元格
So same as before,
和以前一样
I take a closest cell the goal,
我会选择离目标更近的格子
generate trajectories, that is,
然后生成轨迹 这些轨迹会产生碰撞
that all of these collides and close that cell.
然后我会关闭那个单元格
Of the remaining open cells,
的对于剩下的打开单元格
this upper right one is closest or the one with the best heuristic.
右上方这个是离目标最近的 或者说它的启发值最小
So I repeat the process,
因此 我继续处理它
on and on, until I reach the goal.
就这样 直到我们到达目标
Now, let's look at what this trajectory
现在 把这些东西擦掉
really looks like by getting rid of some of the clutter.
让我们来看一下 最终轨迹是什么样的
And what we're left with is a continuous path,
我们得到的是一条连续的路径
that might not be the smoothest solution to our planning problem.
对于我们的规划问题 它可能不是一条最平滑的解
Indeed we can easily find examples of environment,
确实 我们很容易构造出这样的环境
where the resulting path doesn't look very good compared to
在那里 算法生成的路径
what human drivers would have done in this situation.
无法与人工选择的路径相媲美
And that's not the only problem.
而且 算法的问题不止这一条
Sometimes, everyday stuff fails to even find the solution when one actually exists.
有时候 一些小东西就会让算法找不出存在的解
For example, let's go back to the stage in
举个例子 我们回到刚才的地方
the algorithm and consider what would happen if the map were slightly changed.
考虑一下 如果我们把地图稍作调整 会发生什么
In this case, we would have made all the same decisions up until this point.
这种情况下 我们开始的决策和刚才一样 直到我们到达这个位置
But now we have close this crucial cell.
现在 我们的选择是 关闭这个非常关键的单元格
Clearly, there is a path to the goal that could be reached.
显然 这个格子有一条通向目标的路径
But in these circumstances,
但是 在这个例子中
Hybrid A* will not find any.
混合 A* 并没有找出来这条路
We can reduce the likelihood of this problem by increasing the resolution of
为了降低这种问题发生的几率 我们可以为我们的地图添加更多解
our grid or adding a third dimension to the search space for the heading.
或者给我们的搜索空间添加第三维 也就是朝向
Indeed, this would allow us not to close this position in the map for all headings
实际上 后者可以使我们在某些朝向下不会去关闭图上这个位置
but only for a specific range which may allow us to find the solution in this-
只会在特定情况下才会关闭格子 那样我们就可以在这张图上找到解了